<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity on Sajid Mahmood</title><link>https://sajidmahmood.tech/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on Sajid Mahmood</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyrights © 2022, Sajid Mahmood; All rights are reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sajidmahmood.tech/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Password Managers and their Role in Online Safety and Security</title><link>https://sajidmahmood.tech/post/02-password_managers_and_their_role_in_online_safety_and_security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sajidmahmood.tech/post/02-password_managers_and_their_role_in_online_safety_and_security/</guid><description>
Table of Contents What are Password Managers? What Problem they Solve? Features of Password Managers Proprietary Password Managers LastPass: 1Password: Dashlane: FOSS Password Managers KeePass: Padloc: Bitwarden: Some honorable mentions: Why to use FOSS Password Managers? Bitwarden: A Short Intro Bitwarden: Premium Features Bitwarden in Action Conclusion Checkout the video as well:
1) What are Password Managers? A computer program which acts as a wallet for storing, managing passwords as well as offer the feature to generate strong and complicated passwords for applications and services.</description></item><item><title>Importance of Good Password Hygiene</title><link>https://sajidmahmood.tech/post/01-importance_of_good_password_hygiene/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sajidmahmood.tech/post/01-importance_of_good_password_hygiene/</guid><description>
Table of Contents Importance of Good Password Hygiene Don’t Use Weak Passwords Examples of weak passwords How to check your Password Strength? List of most common passwords: What it takes to make a strong password? Passphrase Passphrase Best Practice: Advantages over a traditional password: Tips for Keeping your Passwords &amp;amp; Passphrases Safe Use a Password and Passphrase Generators For password generation, use an online tool like this: For Passphrases, use a tool like this: Closing Thoughts Checkout the video as well.</description></item></channel></rss>